Introduction

A design and production manager with great communication, computer and analytical skills, experienced in a very wide range of digital and analogue print disciplines.

The ability to pull together disparate tools to create workflows and systems that are easier to use, more effective and efficient.

I'm "the guy" people gravitate towards when something needs to happen.

Personal Details

Name: Reeve Schragger

Address: Unit 10, 14 Lillimur Road, Ormond VIC 3204

Mobile: 0423 707 276

E-mail: reeve@whitestudio.net.au

Tertiary: Bachelor of Arts - Industrial Design (Graphics and Computing Minors)

Education

Tertiary

Bachelor of Arts in Product Design - Curtin University, Western Australia - 1989-1993 1 Semester- Bachelor of Engineering (Passed) - University of Western Australia - 1988

Other

First Aid (1990 & 2017)

High School

Gifted and Talented and Language Programme - Mt Lawley Senior High (1983-87)

Personal Strengths

Excellent understanding of systems, especially computer and workflow systems.

Has worked on a very wide range of digital print systems from ultra wide to small formats and a huge range of substrates through many different industries.

A firm believer in the "one percenter" idea of making constant tiny improvements that build upon themselves.

Good business foundations and the ability to think through strategies and implications of actions.

Well-liked and easy to work with, inspiring loyalty in my staff.

Clearance for secure Government Print (State of Victoria)

Computer Skills

Have always been able to operate computer programs across PC and Mac platforms at an advanced level. Some examples of programs I have high proficiency in include;

FileMaker Pro, Applescript®, Illustrator, PhotoShop, Acrobat, Indesign, Pitstop, Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Word, Pageflex, DirectSmile

Work History

2021

Customer Success Engineer – Pictureworks Pty Ltd

Former colleagues employed me to try bring a different perspective to this position as they were familiar with my abilities and work ethic. I saw after 5 months that the position itself wasn't creating value and I was not satisfied to be a "hanger-on" for years until the company matured to where my talents could be the asset they envisaged. Management posited that the experiment was badly affected by circumstances and asked I include them as a reference to assure future employers. They also assured that they consider me someone they would like to work with in the future.

2013-2021

Prepress Manager - Doculink Pty Ltd

Re-vamped workflows to achieve vastly quicker throughput but also much greater accuracy. Extra time saved allowed me to be able to prototype packaging, do special projects and create multiple automations.

Automated internal and client specific projects thereby making these clients reliant on us to be able to achieve their goals.

One example is an app that downloads json information from government client's website, constructs orders from that info and downloads relevant PDF files. Then the system creates print files and sends them to multiple different hot folders to print (eg. stapling, punching combinations etc) and finally an upload is made to eParcel for despatching final product.

Wrote a number of small apps to automate repetitive tasks. For example a "send to proof" Applescript that can format an email with job number, client, relevant addresses, relevant message and file attached using only 1 mouse click and 3 keystrokes.

2007-2013

Prepress Manager - On Demand Pty Ltd

Managed Prepress team

Variable data jobs, Direct Mail, Smile media, Pageflex, Barcoding, secure printing etc

Troubleshooting printing issues, managing RIP systems and hot folders for web and sheetfed digital presses, training staff and clients

Ran complex projects such as large tenders, Government work and

Helped implement the world's first digital only ISO 12647 Process standard offset workflow and was audited and certified by Ugra

2006-Present

White Studio Imaging Pty Ltd.

Consult to Industry - overflow and temp work at digital print operations, supply high end artwork and data driven graphics capabilities (eg barcoding) to trade clients without their own capabilities.

2005-2006

2IC - Square 1 Images - Digital and Screen Print Company

Ran all graphics and technical operations for company. Helped develop the UV Flatbed operation, did all art and print for screenprint, vinyl cut and digital print operations.

Some highlights included

MSAC interior and exterior cladding, printing directly to pre-lasercut panels.

Reece showroom prints onto clear acrylic

Co-Developed full-graphic glass kitchen splashbacks

2004-2005

Production and Factory Manager for Evan Evans Flags and Banners

Responsible for all production, operation and factory matters

Reduced the alarming error rate through simple information process improvements

Manage a factory staff of 15 people, numerous subcontractors through 8 different production workflows, from inkjet through to world leading direct-to-fabric printing.

Completed exhaustive task description dossiers for all employees as part of ISO 9002 process..

Oversaw production and distribution for the International Deaflympic Games, most of the Melbourne City Council banner sites, the Defence Force flags and many blue chip clients and agencies. Prepared the Tender for 4 sections of the 2006 Commonwealth Games.

1999-2004

Manager of ExpoGraphics - Digital Print and Signage Department of Expohire, Victoria's largest Exhibition Building Company.

Tasks include running the Expographics department as an internal business unit. All aspects of a business were my responsibility

Design management, both creative and process. Network and server upkeep.

Account managing 9 internal teams including 2 located interstate. Every sign was fully costed, quoted and invoiced. As they were internal clients, I also provided training and sales support including consultations with end users to assist in marketing to their accounts.

Strategic and workflow planning including designing, writing and implementing a computer application that allowed for an almost doubling of production with almost zero capital injection and disproportionately small increases in labour. Gains were achieved by homogenising the workflow, automating repetitive tasks and simplifying the tasks of the specialists to just their speciality.

Managed all casual and full time labour in 2 sub-divisions

Production management, purchasing, stock control, outsourcing, invoicing, record keeping and backup Annually designed and ran tender process to achieve huge savings in certain supplies by making suppliers compete for our large account.

1986-1999

Digital Signage production - Ascot Sign Co, Perth, Western Australia

One of the first digital signmakers in Perth. A very lean, very profitable company due to good design helping in the management of material and people.

Some of the systems developed during my time were still being used 10 years after I left to keep contracts with major companies such as Transperth Bus livery.

Referees

Professional

Mr. Andrew Smith

Managing Director, Pictureworks Group

Mobile: +61 402 224 043 Email: andrew.smith@pictureworks.com.au

Mrs. Kim Mitchell

Managing Director at Doculink Pty Ltd

Mobile: 0419 552 163 Email: kmitchell@doculink.com.au

Mr. Agilen Jacob Kandan

eCommerce Manager at Lithocraft Pty Ltd

Mobile: 0401 854 145 Email: agilenk@gmail.com

Mr Mal Campbell

Managing Director, Geelong Print Solutions

Mobile: 0412 866 196

Personal

Mr. Ian Raizon

Lasky Raizon Property Group Mobile: 0419 690 995